Guide to the Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers, 1930s-2017 RL.11082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Events, 1991-2016; 1
  - Salute of Arts and Culture to Diplomacy, US-Russian diplomatic relations bicentennial, Washington DC, 2007 Nov. 15 (Box 99)
  - Overcoming Nuclear Danger conference, with M. Gorbachev, Harvard, 2007 Dec. 4-5 (Box 99)
  - General events, 2008 (Box 99)
  - Rowan University lecture, commemorating the Glassboro summit, 2008 Mar. 11 (Box 99)
  - Russia Balance Sheet, CSIS advisory meeting, 2008 June 13 (Box 99)
  - Baltic cruise on Sea Cloud II, 2008 July 5-20 (Box 99)
  - Center for Citizen Initiatives 25th anniversary celebration, 2008 Sept. 14-18 (Box 99)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace conference on Rethinking US-Russia Relations, Arlie House, VA, 2008 Sept. 22-23 (Box 99)
  - A Diplomatic Action Plan on Nuclear Issues, Hoover Inst., 2008 Oct. 8-10 (Box 99)
  - Reflections on Peaceful Coexistence and Intellectual Freedom conference, Harvard, 2008 Oct. 24 (Box 99)
  - General events, 2009 (Box 99)
  - Symposium on East Europe, University of Wisconsin, Eau Claire, 2009 Apr. 2-4 (Box 99)
  - How to Prevent a New Cold War, high-level expert group meeting, InterAction Council, 2009 May 6; 2 folders (Box 99)
    Includes Superpower Illusions draft
  - Eisenhower-Khruschev symposium, 2009 Sept. 25-26 (Box 99)
  - Council for the National Interest political pilgrammage to Israel, 2009 Oct. 30-Nov. 9 (Box 99)
  - General events, 2010 (Box 99)
  - Council on Foreign Relations national conference, 2010 June 10-12 (Box 99)
  - General events, 2011 (Box 99)
  - Security for the Global World conference, Munich, 2011 Mar. 23 (Box 99)
  - North Pacific cruise, Princess Cruises, 2011 May 2-30 (Box 99)
  - Volga cruises, Russia, 2011 July 13-Aug. 1 (Box 99)
  - Global Zero summit, Reagan Presidential Library, 2011 Oct. 11-12 (Box 99)
  - Open World Leadership Center, Wellesley College lecture; Omaha and Boston, 2011 Oct. 25-27 (Box 99)
  - New Policy Forum: Policymakers' Responsibility in a Changing World: The Mediterranean; Montpelier, France, 2011 Nov. 24-25 (Box 99)
  - General events, 2016 (Box 115)
- Personal Papers, 1939-2015; 1
  The Matlocks' Personal Papers series contains two subseries: Correspondence, which consists of various family correspondence collected and sent by the Matlocks during their Foreign Service years, and all correspondence files (arranged chronologically) following Jack Matlock's retirement in 1991. The Correspondence subseries of the Personal Files overlaps with materials in the Foreign Service Series; there is correspondence from family members in both series. The Personal Correspondence arrived at Rubenstein pre-separated by the Matlocks, and tends to be letters between Jack and Rebecca and their immediate family, particularly their children and Jack's mother, Nellie Matlock. The topics of these letters range vastly from logistical and routine to-dos to introsepctive and personal feelings about particular events, ambitions, and people -- the "Personal" classification refers to the correspondents themselves, not the topics or content of the letters. There is additional correspondence from family and friends in the Foreign Service series, so researchers should refer to both series for a fuller account of these relationships.
  The remaining Personal Files series contains assorted family business, including telephone messages, address books, and files relating to specific hobbies and interests of the Matlocks. There are also materials documenting their family life, raising children and running households, while abroad in the Foreign Service in the mid-twentieth century.
  - Correspondence, 1950-2015; 1
    - RM employment applications, 1950 (Box 104)
    - Correspondence (general), 1950s (Box 104)
    - JM correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 104)
    - JM queries to editors, 1953-1959 (Box 104)
      Some overlap with Foreign Service and Academia series; includes notes and correspondence re: Russian translating, Russian literature
    - Correspondence (general), 1954-1956; 2 folders (Box 104)
    - JM logs: mail, finances, some correspondence, 1956 (Box 104)
    - Correspondence from family, 1950s; 3 folders (Box 104)
    - Frank Matlock (JM's brother) letters, clippings, 1958-1961 (Box 104)
    - Correspondence with the children, 1960s-1970s (Box 104)
      RM/JM letters to and received by their children
    - Correspondence from family, 1960s; 3 folders (Box 104)
    - Correspondence from family, 1970-1973; 2 folders (Box 104)
    - Correspondence with Jim Matlock, 1970s; 4 folders (Box 105)
      While at Emory, elsewhere
    - Correspondence with Nell Matlock, 1970s (Box 105)
    - Correspondence with Hugh Matlock, 1975-1977 (Box 105)
    - Correspondence with Joe Matlock, 1976-1978 (Box 105)
    - Correspondence with the Schomackers, 1970s (Box 105)
      Matlock family friends, guardians for children at times
    - Correspondence with family, 1974-1980s; 6 folders (Box 105)
    - Correspondence (general), 1991-1993; 14 folders (Box 106)
    - Correspondence (general), 1993-1996; 16 folders (Box 107)
    - Correspondence (general), 1996-2001; 17 folders (Box 108)
    - Correspondence (general), sorted A-Z, 1996-2001; 25 folders (Box 110)
      General correspondence files arranged alphabetically by JM and his staff; these files overlap other general correspondence from 1996-2001. Researchers should review both sets of correspondence if searching for a particular topic or letter.
    - Correspondence (general), 2001-2015, undated; 23 folders (Box 109)
  - Personal files, 1939-2000s; 2
    - Biographical materials for JM, 1970s-2000s (Box 111)
    - JM file kept by Mrs. Emma Leah Perrett, Old Peck School, Greensboro, NC, 1939-1991 (Box 111)
      Former teacher's photographs of JM's 6th grade class, a valentine from JM to Mrs. Peckett, and clippings about JM's career
    - Greensboro Daily News end of WWII newspapers, 1944 (Box 111)
    - RM and JM wedding clipping, 1949 (Box 111)
    - RM photographs of Vermont architecture, submitted to Vermont Life Magazine, 1955 (Box 111)
    - Finances (ledger), 1957 (Box 111)
    - Travel souvenirs, 1960s (Box 111)
      Bag tags, other airplane and ship ephemera collected from Matlocks' travels in early years of Foreign Service
    - Family travels/vacations, 1960s (Box 111)
      Itineraries, notes, research
    - Portraits of JM, 1960s-2000s (Box 111)
    - Family snapshots/photographs, 1960s (Box 111)
      Likely some overlap with the Foreign Service: Early subseries.
    - Family passport photographs, 1960s-1980s, undated (Box 111)
    - Family news clippings, 1940s-1960s (Box 111)
    - Mementoes and brochures from African vacation planning, 1960s (Box 111)
      Likely some overlap with the Foreign Service: Early subseries
    - Nannies, maids, and servants, 1961-1963 (Box 111)
      Research, correspondence, recruitment, and reference letters for different hired help who assisted the Matlocks with their children in Europe and Africa
    - Children's education, 1960s (Box 111)
      Vouchers, correspondence, invoices for tuition
    - Postage stamps information: Africa, 1960s (Box 111)
    - Audio equipement and tapes, 1967-1970 (Box 111)
    - Book orders, 1950s-1970; 2 folders (Box 111)
    - Nature, birdwatching, fishing in Zanzibar, 1959-1960s (Box 111)
    - Learning Swahili (notes), 1967 (Box 111)
    - Family trip to Scandinavia, 1975 (Box 111)
    - Girl Scout Troop 1535, Washington DC, 1970s (Box 111)
      Nell and RM were active participants
    - RM Report: Tassajara Bread Book, 1979 Feb. (Box 111)
      Notes from cooking/experimentation
    - Russian literature suggested reading by JM, 1970s (Box 111)
    - Fountain pens, 1980s-2000s (Box 111)
      JM's test pages for different inks
    - JM archive codes, notes, undated (Box 111)
      References JM's Diaries and other personal journals, explaining different codes/keys
    - International Design Corporation, 1985-1989; 2 folders (Box 111)
      Plans and drafts for an art agency by JM and RM, importing/representing international artists
    - Subpoena and investigation by Office of Government Ethics re: JM consulting post-retirement, 1993; 5 folders (Box 112)
      Includes photocopies of 1980s documents, transcripts of ABC network appearances by JM, contracts, correspondence, other legal materials
    - Drawings of RM and JM by unknown artist, 1990s (Box 112)
      Signed sketches, but signature is illegible
    - Photographs of RM and JM in post-Foreign Service activities, 1990s-2000s; 3 folders (Box 112)
      Assorted snapshots, photographs of other politicians with JM, photographs of JM and Diego Asencio, RM and JM portrait from a cruise, various events/appearances (unidentified)
    - Address and telephone contacts, 1960s (Box 112)
      2 books
    - Address and contact list, 1991 Dec. (Box 112)
    - Address book, 1993 (Box 112)
    - Contacts in Moscow, 1997 (Box 112)
    - Addresses and contacts list, 1999 (Box 112)
    - JM address book, 1990? (Box 112)
    - Phone messages, 1995-1997; 3 folders (Box 112)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1980-2016; 740 items
  Arrangement
  Chronologically within subseries
  The Audiovisual Materials series contains 380 audiocassettes, 58 microcassettes, 299 VHS videocassettes, and 4 DVDs, arranged chronologically within eight subseries: Arts; Interviews; Lectures, Speeches, and Remarks; Press Briefs; Proceedings of Russian Parliament and Supreme Soviet; Seminars, Forums, and Roundtables; Town Meetings; and Miscellaneous.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Digital audio and video access files are available for many of the resources listed in the Audiovisual Materials series, and may be requested by selecting the associated digital set in the "Request for Onsite Use" page. For further information regarding access to these files, or to request digitization and access to of an analog resource not yet reformatted, contact Research Services.
  - Arts
    - The Yale Russian Chorus Performances in Moscow, Joseph T. Barna, 1987 (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0054)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0460, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0054.mp4)
    - Yale Russian Chorus in Moscow, 1987 Joseph Barna (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0069)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0475, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0069.mp4)
    - R. Matlock-Photo Exhibit-Dom Kino, 1989 (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0121)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0527, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0121.mp4)
    - R. Matlock - Photo Exhibit, Photojournalist's Club, Moscow, 1989 (Box AV19, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0204)
    - Voznesensky Poetry Reading, Tchaikovsky Hall, 1989-02-09 (Box AV21, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0281)
    - Opening of R's photo show (Dom Kino), 5/89; Paddle Tennis Tournament, 5/20/89; Trip to Vladimir/Suzdal 5/28-29/89; Trip to Pet Market, 1989-05 (Box AV22, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0298)
    - "взгляд" with Aksyonov, 1989-11-17 (Box AV20, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0244)
    - Aksyonov at Spaso House Seminar, 1989-11-17 (Box AV20, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0245)
    - "Nika" Awards - 1989, 1989-12-30; 1990-01-13 (broadcast date) (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0123)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0529, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0123.mp4)
    - Музыка и Гельмана, 1990 (Box AV07, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0015)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0016, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0015.mp3)
    - Время, Радзи́нский interview, 1990-01-11/1990-01-12 (Box AV21, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0270)
    - R. Matlock Opening of Ryijy Exhibit in Tretyakov Moscow, 1990-01-19 (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0113)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0519, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0113.mp4)
    - R Matlock - Ryijy Exhibit, Moscow, 1990-01-19 (Box AV22, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0297)
    - Side 3/of 3 Amb. Matlock at Spaso with Aleksey Karavlov book author freelancer, 1990-03-03 (Box AV14, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0259)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0260, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0259.mp3)
    - An Evening of Poetry at Spaso House, 1990-05-24 (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0095)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0501, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0095.mp4)
    - Georgian Dancers, 1990-06-24 (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0110)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0516, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0110.mp4)
    - Nika Awards, 2850 for Matlocks, 1990-12-28; 1991-01-20 (broadcast date) (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0124)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0530, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0124.mp4)
    - Boy's Choir from Nizhni Novgorod, Easter 1991, at Spaso House (Box AV07, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0009)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0010, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0009.mp3)
    - R Matlock's Photo Exhibit, Glinka Museum Moscow, 1991-02-22 (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0102)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0508, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0102.mp4)
    - SCULPTURE TODAY! (Final), undated (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0021)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0429, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0021.mp4)
    - USSR/ART, undated (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0045)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0451, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0045.mp4)
    - SCULPTURE TODAY!, IDC at Hartford, undated (Box AV03, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0088)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0494, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0088.mp4)
    - Rebecca's Photo Exhibit, Дом Фотожурналистов, undated (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0127)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0533, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0127.mp4)
    - Nemirov Poetry Reading, undated (Box AV19, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0213)
    - Mandelshtam, undated (Box AV21, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0274)
  - Interviews
    - Matlock Interview on McNeill-Lehrer NewsHour, 1987-03-26 (Box AV04, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0122)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0528, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0122.mp4)
    - WSJ D'Anestasio Interview of Ambassador Matlock-Deep Background, 1987-04-30 (Box AV17, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0365)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0365, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0368.mp3)
    - Interview of Ambassador Matlock, 1987-05-07 (Box AV17, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0368)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0368, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0371.mp3)
    - Face to Face in USSR Ambassador Matlock Series Tape WKBW-TV Buffalo N.Y., 1987-06-13 (Box AV02, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0059)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0465, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0059.mp4)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview with Warren Salinger, Exectuive Director of the Dana McLean Greeley Foundation for Peace and Justice, on Boston Radio WCRB, 1987-06-24 (Box AV15, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0302)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0302, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0305.mp3)
    - U.S. Ambassador Jack Matlock with Warren Salinger, Greeley Foundation, Interview in Moscow, 1987-06-25 (Box AV17, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0353)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0353, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0356.mp3)
    - Matlock & Elizabeth Pond Christian-Science Monitor, 1987-07-06 (Box AV15, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0304)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0304, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0307.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview by Korotich of Ogonyok, 1987-07-20 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0308)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0308, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0311.mp3)
    - Jim Hogland Backgrounder with Ambassador Matlock, 1987-07-23 (Box AV15, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0305)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0305, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0308.mp3)
    - Tim Shanker, Chi Trib on Record Interview with Ambassador Matlock, 1987-07-24 (Box AV15, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0306)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0306, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0309.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock interview with Jim Hermens of Focus on Youth: American Focus, 1987-08-14 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0311)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0311, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0314.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview with Walter Friedenberg, Scripts Howard Newspapers, 1987-08-26 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0313)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0313, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0316.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview by Newsweek's Joyce Barathan, 1987-08-26 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0314)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0314, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0317.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview by NBC John Cochran, 1987-09-03 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0316)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0316, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0319.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock on the record CBS interview with Wyatt Andrews, 1987-09-07 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0318)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0318, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0321.mp3)
    - Amb. Matlock Interview with Bob Adams, St. Louis Post Dispatch, 1987-10-09 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0324)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0324, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0327.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock's BEYOND WAR interview, 1987-10-09 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0325)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0325, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0328.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview with Peter Slevin of Miami Paper, 1987-11-19 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0335)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0335, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0338.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview with Tom Shanker, 1987-11-20 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0334)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0334, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0337.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock on camera Interview with ABC, 1987-11-21 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0337)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0337, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0340.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock with AP at Spaso, 1987-11-21 (Box AV16, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0338)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0338, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0341.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock CNN and on-camera NBC Interview Pre-Summit, 1987-12-01 (Box AV11, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0144)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0145, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0144.mp3)
    - Breakthrough at Reykjavik, Ch. 7 News (Matlock), 1987-12-11 (Box AV22, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0294)
    - Matlock - Moscow TV Interview, 1988-01 (Box AV20, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0249)
    - Amb. Matlock's Interview with Ron Koestler, 1988-01-20 (Box AV09, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0088)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0089, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0088.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview-"Sov. Rossiya" at Spaso House with Sergei Volovets, 1988-02-05 (Box AV11, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0149)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0150, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0149.mp3)
    - Matlock - D. Willis, 1988-02-06 (Box AV22, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0293)
    - CNN Interviews with Jean McKenzie, 1988-03-01 (Box AV11, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0162)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0163, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0162.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interviewed by Vlad Pozner from Soviet TV, 1988-03-10 (Box AV11, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0160)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0161, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0160.mp3)
    - Time w/ Mike Joyce, 1988-03-24 (Box AV08, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0062)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0063, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0062.mp3)
    - May 1988 Discussion of History Textbooks, 1988-05 (Box AV01, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0001)
      - Digital video file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0409, Video-file RL11082-VHS-0001.mp4)
    - Interview with Lapham for TV Service, 1988-05-02 (Box AV17, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0362)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0362, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0365.mp3)
    - TCA-88-05-05 Side A: Interview with Siberian Pravda- Irkutsk; Side B: Interview with Gosteleradio TV on the exhibit floor-Irkutsk, 1988-05-05; 1988-05-05 (Box AV17, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0363)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0363, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0366.mp3)
    - TCA-88-05-09 Interview with J. Barmathan, Newsweek Interview (Bleground), 1988-05-09 (Box AV17, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0364)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0364, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0367.mp3)
    - Ambassador Interviews with CBC, BBC, Jurun San. Keskisvo, 1988-06-02 (Box AV11, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0153)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0154, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0153.mp3)
    - TASS Interview of Ambassador Matlock, 1988-07-03 or 1989-07-03 (Box AV12, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0191)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0192, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0191.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock with USA Today on record, 1988-07-05 (Box AV12, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0192)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0193, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0192.mp3)
    - Ambassador with Vechernaya Moskva, 1988-09-15 (Box AV12, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0184)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0185, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0184.mp3)
    - Amb. Matlock--Nedelya Interview at Spaso House, 1988-10-04 (Box AV09, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0097)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0098, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0097.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock's Interview with TRUD, 1988-12-02 (Box AV09, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0091)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0092, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0091.mp3)
    - Amb. Matlock's Interview with "Moskovskiy Komsomolets", 1988-12-02 (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0103)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0104, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0103.mp3)
    - Interview with Matlocks, 1988-12-24 (Box AV21, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0276)
    - Matlock interview on Добрый Вечер, Москва, 1989 (Box AV19, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0203)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview "Tbilisi" Paper, 1989-01-05 (Box AV10, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0105)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0106, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0105.mp3)
    - Ambassaor Matlock Interview with Soviet Journalists at Spaso House, 1989-01-26 (Box AV09, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0098)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0099, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0098.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock's 02/02/1989 Interview with Yunost Radio, 1989-02-02 (Box AV09, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0092)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0093, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0092.mp3)
    - Soviet TV Report on Dom Kino, Interview with Ambassador Matlock, 1989-03-24 (Box AV19, Video-cassette RL11082-VHS-0202)
    - Ambassador Matlock Interview by Yunost Radio, 1989-03-25 (Box AV09, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0069)
      - Digital audio file (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-0070, Audio-file RL11082-CS-0069.mp3)
    - Ambassador Matlock with Yunosti Radio, 1989-03-25 (Box AV17, Audio-cassette RL11082-CS-0369)